It's The Futurama Holiday
Spectacular brought to you by...
Ah, the Xmas season.
Who wants a delicious
unshelled nut?
Ooh, I'll have one.
It's "nut" so good.
What's wrong, Fry? Are you
regretting another wasted year?
I don't know.
Something about Xmas
just doesn't feel
like Christmas.
Santa's coming!
Initiate defenses!
God rest
ye merry gentlemen
in peace.
Can someone please explain how
you celebrate this crazy holiday?
Preferably in song.
It's the violentest
season of the year
When Kringle-bot come
dispensing mugs of Xmas fear
Sugar plummy visions will be dancing in your head
When I cane you
from the comfort of my sled
On Xmas Eve,
we don our gay apparel
Kevlar vests, asbestos stockings and a barrel
And if Grandma's Xmas fruitcake
finally reaches critical mass
It can be re-gifted
straight to Santa's ass
But the ornamental armaments
are merely superficial
The tinsel and the trappings
are just icing on the missile
The one thing that you need to
make your Xmas Day splendiferous
Is a pine tree
A pine tree that's coniferous
We have to have a pine tree
that's coniferous
You're welcome.
You know, Santa may have killed
Scruffy, but he makes a good point.
What we need is an
old-fashioned pine tree.
Cram it, Virginia.
Pine trees have been
extinct for over 800 years.
Professor,
maybe there's some way
to bring the pine
trees back to life.
Like we did with
the barking snakes.
Pine trees aren't
barking snakes.
They won't just turn up
in a salad at Olive Garden.
But there is one hope and,
as usual, it's Norwegian.
Behold!
The Svalbard
Global Seed Vault.
Since 2008, the vault has preserved
seeds of every known plant species,
in case of extinction.
And I brought
a few seeds of my own.
Halt! What's your business
pokey-poking about the seed vault?
Guardian of mankind's precious
botanical heritage there?
We just want to come in
and rummage about a bit.
Oh, so... Okay.
Yo, ABBA,
what's that next door?
That's the Germ
Warfare Repository.
It's so close.
Is there any chance
of cross-contamination?
No.
Now, your pine trees
were all chopped down
to make emergency toilet paper
during the Fifty-Year Squirts.
Lucky the seeds have been
preserved here in the vault there.
What's that splork on them?
It's not germs, is it?
No.
Now that's a tree
worth chopping down.
Indeed,
'tis a lovely tree.
'Twill truly be my
finest Xmas ever.
That's what my
poll numbers need.
Happy voters enjoying
some holiday cheer.
As your vice-president, I
order you to steal that tree.
My fellow Earthicans,
welcome to the annual White
House Xmas-tree lighting,
brought to you by
Gunderson's Nuts.
Gunderson!
Oh, no! Could the seed have been contaminated
by a virus from
the germ vault?
Yeah, I suppose.
Wait. This could be a good
thing. That weaponized virus
made the sickly, little tree
grow big and strong.
Wait. This could be
a good thing.
Reforestation has begun.
Geez, with these...
Arguably, this could
be a good thing.
The planet has returned
to its primeval state.
Earth is just the way it was
before the white man came.
Good news.
All these pine trees are
fighting global warming
by producing oxygen.
Happy now, Gore?
Yeah.
But I'd be happier if
I had a set of lungs.
Wait a second. Oxygen levels
are rising too rapidly.
10%, 20%, 60%.
As long as it
doesn't hit 70.
80%.
You know, I don't recall having
done anything for a while,
but I still feel
I deserve a smoke.
Hey, cool.
The air is on fire.
Ho, ho, ho.
Everyone's dead.
Stay tuned for another tale
of holiday hilarity.
Now back to
the Gunderson's Nuts
Holiday Spectacular
featuring Futurama.
Okay, crew.
Xmas break is over.
It's time to destroy these
gifts we forgot to deliver.
Whoa, whoa, whoa!
How come we get off for every dumb human holiday,
but not for
robot holidays?
Oh, Lord.
Not Robanukah.
I'm talking about Robanukah,
the holiest six and a half
weeks in the robot calendar.
That's just a fake holiday you make
up every year to get out of work.
Yeah. If it's real,
how come there's no song that
explains how to celebrate it?
Because there is.
Hit it.
Hit what?
I placed instruments
under your seats.
Play them or I'll break them over your heads.
Robanukah may sound
as if it's Jewish
But its ancient-sounding
customs are exceptionally newish
So take a hearty swallow
from your robo-Kiddush cup
Which will give me time
to quickly make them up
Do you spin
a dreidel made from clay?
Mine is called a droid-el and
it's rigged to make you pay
Do you eat these yummy,
tin-wrapped chocolate coins?
Better. We got fem-bots
with illegal five-speed groins
Shalom, Ruth and Esther.
Why with the music
so loud?
Would it kill him to turn up
the heat a little in here?
By far, the most
important thing is oil
To keep the lamp light burning
or to help the latkes broil
No, we pour the holy lubricant
out from this sacred vessel
into this blessed
pit so they can wrestle
The extra made-up touch
that makes Robanukah so special
is the oil in which the
nasty fem-bots wrestle
We shall now begin the
traditional oil wrestling.
Will the referee bring out the
ceremonial cruse of petroleum oil?
Thank you, Abraham.
Not in the hair, please.
I just had it did.
Oh, no.
These broads are supposed to
wrestle for six and a half weeks,
but there's only enough petroleum
oil for four and a half weeks.
We're still
getting paid, right?
I told you it's an audition!
Bender, four and a half weeks of
oil wrestling sounds like plenty.
This isn't
a lousy reform Robanukah.
We need more petroleum oil!
I got me some whale oil,
some squirrel oil.
Not kosher!
It has to be petroleum oil!
Do you not give a damn about the
hallowed traditions of Robanukah?
I reckon I do not.
Anyways, Earth done run out
of petroleum oil.
I tried to warn you.
One unit of free,
limitless solar power, please.
That'll be,
I don't know, 10 bucks.
Can you make change
for a Nobel Prize?
Man, can't we just make
more petroleum oil?
I'm afraid not, son.
Petroleum only forms
when organic matter
is subjected to intense pressure
for hundreds of millions of years.
I can't wait that long.
I've got ADD.
This is so unfair.
I don't wrestle dry, Bender.
I went to Vassar.
Professor, I want you to look
these poor floozies in the eye
and tell them their
oil-wrestling days are over.
I suppose there could be a
minute quantity of petroleum left,
but it would be insanely
deep within the Earth
at pressures so
dangerously high...
Let's go, already!
Setting Bachman Turners
to Overdrive.
We're getting pretty deep.
Look! Mole coffins.
Oh, no.
We tunneled into a tunnel.
What's that loud, boring sound
you'll hear when I stop talking?
It's an albino humping worm.
Why do they call it that?
Because it doesn't
have any pigment.
What's our depth, Captain?
Forty kilometers, 50.
There must be petroleum oil
down here somewhere.
Go deeper. Deeper!
No, Bender. The ship can't
withstand this much pressure.
Sometimes it falls apart
just sitting in the hangar.
Professor, I've never asked for anything before,
but seeing those
fem-bots glistening
with oil means more
to me than life itself.
Call me an old fool, but I believe
the Lord is speaking through you.
Brace yourselves, everyone.
One hundred kilometers.
Two hundred.
I hate to complain
about the heat,
but the air conditioner's
on fire.
My ice cream Manwich!
What the hell
are we doing?
We're all gonna die so this junkyard
golem can celebrate Robanukah.
You vile racist.
Haven't my people
suffered enough?
Now keep drilling for that
petroleum oil, you selfish cowards.
Although, then again, I guess any
kind of oil would be just as...
Not my fault.
I am so great. Bender is great
Bender, Bender, Bender
Man, where'd the time go?
Hey, you guys wanna...
Oh. Right.
They turned
into petroleum oil.
I thought they were selfish,
yet in the end,
it turns out it was I
who thought they were selfish.
Hey, ladies, I found some.
What the...
There was only
enough petroleum oil
for four and a half
weeks of oil wrestling,
but it lasted
500 million years.
It's a miracle.
Happy Robanukah, everyone.
Coming up next, more
thoughtful, interfaith hijinks.
And now,
the unrelated conclusion.
Hello, Fry.
Hey, Fry!
How you doing?
What's up?
LaBarbara, Hermes,
happy Kwanzaa.
We brought a chocolate cake,
but now I'm worried that
might be offensive in some way.
Just sit down.
Happy Kwanzaa,
brother men and sister men.
Well, look at the cat
the cat dragged in.
Kwanzaa tradition
encourages educational gifts.
So I brought Dwight
my book on mathketball.
Whoa!
Let me see that.
I'll sign it for you later.
Man,
it's a cold one out there.
Barbados Slim?
Come in, Barbados.
Look at yourself, all throbbing
and shirtless for the holiday.
I hope you're
ready to celebrate.
All night long, woman.
I'm glad you all could be
here with my family.
Kwanzaa traditions are quite
ancient, dating back over 1,000 years.
Whoa!
If only someone could tell us
more about these traditions.
Oh, yeah.
Hey, Kool-Aid's here.
No, child. That's not
a made-up character.
It's Kwanzaa-bot.
And I'm gonna tell you all
how we celebrate Kwanzaa.
Zoidberg, lay down a beat.
How about I just lay down?
There's seven basic principles
that go to make up Kwanzaa
So sit your asses down and have
some knowledge dropped upon ya
Kujichagulia
And Umoja.
And the rest!
Now we get it
Sit back down
There's gonna be a test
My favorite's Ujamaa
Cooperative economics
Yo, bulldog, I'm talking here
Put away the comics
Ku'umba is another one
It stands for creativity
Like the ever-changing nature
of my sexual proclivities
I think there's one called Nia
but I don't speak Swahili
Something about a pine tree
and an oil-wrestling deal-y?
That's from Xmas and Robanukah
you plagiarizing lout
Yeah, I'm kind of losing interest
here I best be rolling out
But before I go,
the most important thing
What's that, black Santa?
You need seven Kwanzaa candles
that you light up every night
But they best be
made of beeswax
or you all might
as well be white
They must be made of beeswax
or we might as well be white
Well, we got
no beeswax candles,
but these scented regular
wax candles will do just fine.
Girl, those stink sticks are
for single women who take baths.
If your Kwanzaa candles
ain't 100% beeswax,
you bring shame
on your people.
Well, now that won't do.
Husband,
show a little Ku'umba
and fetch some beeswax
before Kwanzaa ends.
Sweet candelabra of
La Habra, LaBarbara.
Isn't this the last night
of Kwanzaa?
Who the hell knows?
Finally, a bee farm that's
open late on Kwanzaa.
Madam, I need beeswax.
You sure you don't need
a little honey, handsome?
Maybe a taste of sweet nectar
straight from the hive?
I just need some beeswax
to make Kwanzaa candles.
Well, that's too darn bad.
There ain't no beeswax
in the whole world.
Oh, no. This could be
the year without a Kwanzaa,
like every year before 1966.
The bees are
acting all crazy
like they been drinking
Tang and cough syrup,
or as I call it,
my Friday night.
My God.
It's Colony Collapse Syndrome. The
bees are swarming with parasites.
They're all dying.
Yeah,
but what a way to go.
"Die young, leave a pretty
corpse," that's what I say.
You should say
something else.
Wait. I know where
we can get beeswax.
From those giant space bees
who nearly killed us,
and we swore we'd
never go back there.
Let's go back there.
To communicate
with the bees,
we'll need to use
these trans-bumbleators.
Bender,
say something in bee talk.
I'm sorry, Bender. What do you
want me to put on the glass?
Okay, if we survive.
Something's wrong.
It's way too quiet.
Like the deadly Prius.
Ah,
here they come.
They're in attack formation.
They're gonna kill us.
That was weird.
It's like the Jдgermeister
air show all over again.
According to Google Hive,
we are at the exact center
of the honeycomb.
And there's a Jamba Juice 0.2 miles that way.
Does that thing tell you
where the queen bee is?
The big, fat, ugly,
compound-eyed, hairy-thoraxed...
Don't be applying
your Eurocentric
standards of
beauty to me, fool.
What's with the
kamikaz-bees?
Man, my hive's
been going buck-wild
since these blood-ganking
butt crabs moved in.
Been there, done that.
They're all infected,
just like the bees on Earth.
Brother-sucking parasites gone
and disrupted our hive mind.
Now, instead of
working in harmony,
my bees just talk
smack to each other.
Are you all black
with yellow stripes
or are you yellow
with black stripes?
Yellow with
black stripes, man.
Why don't you just move along?
Let me ask you something,
you sting my wife?
What kind of
buzzing question is that?
Where do you get the wings
big enough to ask me that?
Okay, gang. We have plenty of
beeswax. Let's get back to the ship.
No, we are not
going anywhere.
I can't abide all
this bee-on-bee conflict.
It's time to African-Americanize these honeybees.
Listen up, bees.
It's Kwanzaa, a time of Umoja.
It means "unity".
You have to learn to
work together again.
The crazy
tablecloth man is right.
It's time to set
aside our differences.
Black stripe, yellow stripe.
At the end of the day, we're just
a couple of darn talking space bees.
Hey, forget about it.
Come here
and give me a sting.
Look. The spirit of Kwanzaa
is killing the parasites.
Yuck!
But, yay!
Thank you, my human brother.
Your message of unity
has touched our souls.
We are once again of
a single hive mind.
Oh, yeah.
Hurray! Kwanzaa-bot's
here to save...
They killed him.
Joyous Kwanzaa, everybody.
Don't worry. The Futurama
crew will be back next year
with all new episodes featuring
Bender, Leela and me, Al Gore,
as Captain Lance Starman.
And from all of us here at
Gunderson's Nuts, happy holidays.